# AHMED AHMED

**Phone**: (651) 417-2022 | **Email**: ahmedahmedmn56@gmail.com | Saint Paul, MN 55107

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedahmed56/| **Portfolio**:https://ahmedahmed5698.github.io/Portfolio/

Full Stack Web Developer with a life-long dedication to learning. Demonstrated leadership with a clear understanding of the five stages of web development to create fully functional websites and web applications. Equipped with the knowledge and expertise to collaboratively with a like-minded team to ensure optimal results for user-centered and technology-centered designs.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages**: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, React.js

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Emerson Process Management**

Instrument Builder (IB)

2014-2015

Chanhassen, MN

Helped build products that companies across the world were ordering. Attained great communication and critical thinking skills by working with a team and solving problems at work.

Tusk Official LLC Freelance Web Developer

2016-Present

Saint Paul, MN

As a freelancer under Tusk Official, I helped design, build, and improve front-end web applications for a variety of clients. Also maintained open communication and feedback in order to meet each client's needs and specifications. Seek opportunities to help clients further realize their vision by providing creative insights and innovative solutions.

RHC LLC 2018-2019

### Freelance Web Developer

Saint Paul, MN

With RHC I developed, design and maintain responsive website. Working with RHC included day to day coding using the full stack - HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, and databases using MySQL to support Web applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: University Of Minnesota, Saint Paul, MN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React.js.